Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Written Work, 24 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box.; 507 Megabytes in 6,369 digital files.
  - "Cinema and Reality", Undated; cuid35257 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - "Circumstances of the Film and Writing", 1978-1980; cuid35258 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - "Clung", Undated; cuid35259 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - "Clutter: Itself", 1981; cuid35260 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Collected E-mail and Internet Works, 1994-2010; cuid36106 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "Colloque des Ecrivains", 1980; cuid35261 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - "Columbus" - Notes, Undated; cuid35262 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - "Commemoration", Undated; cuid35263 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - "Complicity of the Spectator", 1983; cuid35264 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - "Components of a General Theory of Reality", 1975; cuid35265 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Computer Code and Programming Files, 1988-2007; cuid36140 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_20)
    These files include BAS, BVH, E, HTML, INI, LOG, OBJ, and other filetypes.
  - "Computer-Produced Diagrams Concerned With Marginality and Floating Signifiers Within a System of Absences and Fluctuations", Undated; cuid35266 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - "Computer-Produced (Language Generation) or Computer-Modified (Actor Antagonistic Editor) Texts", Undated; cuid35267 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - "Conceptual Art Characteristics", Undated; cuid35268 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - "Conclusions in Relation to Freudian Metapsychology", 1983; cuid35269 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - "The Confused Supplement to Textbook in Thinking, Cut Desert", 1991; cuid35270 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - "Considering The Future of the Planet (The Privilege of the Machine)", Undated; cuid35271 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - "Construct of the Ego", Undated; cuid35272 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - "Construct of the Ego: An Outline", 1984; cuid35273 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - "Consumption", Undated; cuid35274 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - "Consumption (Manuscript III)", Undated; cuid35275 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - "Contemporary Sculpture: Texts", 1977; cuid35276 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - "Continuation of Notes on 'Gulliver's Travels' and Tournier's 'The Ogre', 1978; cuid35277 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - "Continuation of The Diary", Undated; cuid35278 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - "The Contrary", 1985; cuid35279 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - "Contributions to a Musical Aesthetics", Undated; cuid35280 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - "Control, Transform, Master-Slave, Commodity, Tokenization", Undated; cuid35281 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - "Cords (The Sickness VI)", Undated; cuid35282 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - "Corral" by Alan Sondheim and himfffi, 1969-1970; cuid35283 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Undated; cuid35284 (Box 34, Folder 15, 16, Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence With Family, Undated; cuid35285 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - "The Cotton Kingdom", Undated; cuid35286 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - "Counting", Undated; cuid35287 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - "Country", Undated; cuid35288 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - "Criminal America", Undated; cuid35289 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - "Critical-Excessive Writings", 1994; cuid35290 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - "Critical Mind", Undated; cuid35291 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - "Criticism", Undated; cuid35292 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - "Criticisms", Undated; cuid35293 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Critique/Alan Sondheim, Undated; cuid35294 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - "Critique of Postmodernism", Undated; cuid35295 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - "Critique of the Authentic", Undated; cuid35296 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - "Crossambulation", Undated; cuid35297 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - "Culture", Undated; cuid35298 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - "Current Condition of the Screen.txt Saved in the C:\Dos\What.txt After Return Through Inadvertent and Unsolicited Reiteration of an Originary Imaginary Trace", 1994; cuid35299 (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - "Current Sound Texts," Alan Sondheim With Devonna Walker, Voice, Undated; cuid35300 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - "Cut", Undated; cuid35301 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - "Cut Desert", 1994; cuid35302 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "Cybermidrash", 2003; cuid36125 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_5)
    "Cybermidrash" is a collborative multimedia web project between Alan Sondheim and Joel Weishaus.
  - "Cybermind" Email Listserv, 1994-2000; cuid36126 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_6, Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "Da Da", Undated; cuid35303 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - "Dali", Undated; cuid35304 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - "Damaged Life", Undated; cuid35305 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "Damaged Life. Liner Notes", Undated; cuid35306 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - "Dance", Undated; cuid35307 (Box 35, Folder 7, 8, 9, 10)
  - "Dance Description", 1971; cuid35308 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - "Dark Blue of the Air", Undated; cuid35309 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - "Dawn" by Reiner Strasser and Alan Sondheim, 2005; cuid36127 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_7)
    "Dawn" is a multimedia project by Alan Sondheim and Reiner Strasser. Text, photography, and sound is by Alan Sondheim. Musical compositions are composed by Reiner Strasser.
  - "Dawns", Undated; cuid35310 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - "De- ii, i, I, Ø", Undated; cuid35311 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - "Dead End", Undated; cuid35312 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - "Dead Time: The Machinery of Reality", 1981; cuid35313 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - "Death", Undated; cuid35314 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - "Death and Computation", Undated; cuid35315 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - "The Death Car the Suicide", Undated; cuid35316 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - "The Death of American Art," Art and Artists, 1989; cuid35317 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - "Death of Gender", Undated; cuid35318 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - "The Death of Henry Ward Beecher", 1968; cuid35319 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - "Death of Logic, Logical Death", Undated; cuid35320 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - "The Death of Sean Smith", Undated; cuid35321 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - "Death Row Death Row", Undated; cuid35322 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - "Death/Sentencing", 1985; cuid35323 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - "Death Sex; Sex Death", Undated; cuid35324 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - "Debrisfilm", Undated; cuid35325 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - "Decadence", Undated; cuid35326 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - "Decomposition: The Transamerican Avant-Garde," Art Papers, 1989; cuid35327 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - "Deleuze" Email Listserv, 1994; cuid36128 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_8)
  - "Delusion in the Form of a Preface", Undated; cuid35328 (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - "The Departure of Cinema: Treatment", Undated; cuid35329 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - "Deprivation", Undated; cuid35330 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - "Description of a Film", Undated; cuid35331 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - "The Description of the History of Measurement and Substance", Undated; cuid35332 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - "Des Esseintes", Undated; cuid35333 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - "Des Esseintes and Decadence (Con't.)", Undated; cuid35334 (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - "Development of a Generalized Structure Applicable to the Foundations of Most Disciplines," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35335 (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - "Diary Which is Not a Diary in Continuation", Undated; cuid35336 (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - "Differance", Undated; cuid35337 (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - "Discourse on the Civilized", 1975; cuid35338 (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - Disorders of the Real, 1985-1989; cuid35339 (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Disorders of the Real, 1987; cuid35340 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Disorders of the Real: Abstract, 1982; cuid35341 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - "Distinction", Undated; cuid35342 (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - "Documents Relating to the Lectures in Denmark", 1973; cuid35343 (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - "Done For!", Undated; cuid35344 (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - "The Doom Mummy" by William Louis Sørensen, 1971; cuid35345 (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - "Double", Undated; cuid35346 (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - "Dream", Undated; cuid35347 (Box 35, Folder 50)
  - "The Dream of All of You", Undated; cuid35348 (Box 35, Folder 51)
  - "DRG.TXT", Undated; cuid35349 (Box 35, Folder 52)
  - "Dusks", Undated; cuid35350 (Box 35, Folder 53)
  - "E.A.T.", 1983; cuid35351 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - "Economy of Dreams", Undated; cuid35352 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - "Ecriture and Others: Some Writings", 1970-1980; cuid35353 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - "Electronic Music in Concert" by Laura E. Hersh, Brown Daily Herald, April 1968; cuid36114 (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - "Electronic Subjectivity", Undated; cuid35354 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - "Eleven Piece Series", Undated; cuid35355 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - "Ellipse Injection Into Active Visual Field: Stages", 1971; cuid35356 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - "El Oud", Undated; cuid35357 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Email and Online Chat Correspondence, 1994-2009; cuid36148 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_28)
  - "Em/bedded", Undated; cuid35358 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - "Employment", Undated; cuid35359 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - "The Empress/The Retinue", Undated; cuid35360 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - "Engage", 1973; cuid35361 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - "The Enterprise of the Colonels", Undated; cuid35362 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - "The Enterprising Florist", Undated; cuid35363 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - "Errata to The Structure of Reality", Undated; cuid35364 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - "The Establishment of Human Positioning," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35365 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - "Etc.", Undated; cuid35366 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - "Eternal Terminological Return", 1987-1989; cuid35367 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - "Etiquette/Perversion", Undated; cuid35368 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - "Event", Undated; cuid35369 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - "The Event of Your Life. The Event of a Life.", Undated; cuid35370 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - "Everything", Undated; cuid35371 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - "Evocation of the Former Familiar", Undated; cuid35372 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - "Exhaustion of Gender at the Foot of the Hermaphrodite", Undated; cuid35373 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Exhibit Essays by Alan Sondheim for Connie Bostic and George Stone, 1988; cuid35374 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - "Exhibition", Undated; cuid35375 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - "The Exhibition of the Fissured Terrain", Undated; cuid35376 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - "Exhibitionism", Undated; cuid35377 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - "Exile and Others", 1980; cuid35378 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - "The Expansion of a Point Source", Undated; cuid35379 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - "Experimental Writing", Undated; cuid35380 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - "Factory/Craft/'Art' ", Undated; cuid35381 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - "Failure, Ideology, and the World Order: Representative Statements", Undated; cuid35382 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - "Familiarity: Family, Art, and Ideology" by Laura Hayes and Alan Sondheim, 1979; cuid35383 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - "Fantasies…", Undated; cuid35384 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - Fantasms of the Real, 1989; cuid35385 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - "Far Hills Project", Undated; cuid35386 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - "Fashion", Undated; cuid35387 (Box 36, Folder 37)
  - "February 8, 3:00 A.M. 2200", 1988; cuid35388 (Box 36, Folder 38)
  - "Feer", Undated; cuid35389 (Box 36, Folder 39)
  - Fever (Fantasms of the Real), 1989; cuid35390 (Box 37, Folder 1, 2)
  - "Few Tired Lines on the Same Subject", 1985; cuid35391 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "Fibre Bundle", Undated; cuid35392 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "Fiction of Philosophy" Email Listserv, 1994-2000; cuid36129 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_9)
  - "Figure", Undated; cuid35393 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "File: Compute", Undated; cuid35394 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - "File: Exper", Undated; cuid35395 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "File: Iceland", Undated; cuid35396 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "File: New", Undated; cuid35397 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - "File: One", Undated; cuid35398 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - "File: Store", Undated; cuid35399 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - "File: Store.Text", Undated; cuid35400 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - "File: System.Wrk.Text", 1979; cuid35401 (Box 38, Folder 11, 12)
  - "File: Three", Undated; cuid35402 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - "File: Two", Undated; cuid35403 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - "Film", Undated; cuid35404 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - "Film", 1983; cuid35405 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - "Film and Video", Undated; cuid35406 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - "Film Clara", Undated; cuid35407 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - "Film Clusters", Undated; cuid35408 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - "Film for Characters", Undated; cuid35409 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - "The Film in Which I Am Lost", 1984; cuid35410 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - "Film of Weeds and Directions", Undated; cuid35411 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - "Filmscript", Undated; cuid35412 (Box 38, Folder 23, 24)
  - "Filmscript for Denise", Undated; cuid35413 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - "Filmscript: Question and Answer (Period)", Undated; cuid35414 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - "Filmscript: (Smoky Mountains)", Undated; cuid35415 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - "The Film Sleazy", Undated; cuid35416 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - "Film, Theatre, Theater", Undated; cuid35417 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - "Film, Video, and Photography: A Series of Statements", Undated; cuid35418 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - "The First Day of the Smog Alert Everyone Went to Town", Undated; cuid35419 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - "Fissure (Your Voice, Adjacent, Absent)", Undated; cuid35420 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - "Five Texts", 1976-1977; cuid35421 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - "Flight", Undated; cuid35422 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - "Flow, Etc.", Undated; cuid35423 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - "Flying", Undated; cuid35424 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - "Fool of Philosophy", Undated; cuid35425 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - "Footnote: Dust on the Print", Undated; cuid35426 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - "For Al Wilson, Member of Canned Heat, Friend, Guitar Teacher, Who Died a While Back", Undated; cuid35427 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - "Force and Speaking for Oneself", Undated; cuid35428 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - "The Foreplay of Identity", Undated; cuid35429 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - "Forgery", Undated; cuid35430 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - "Found Poem", Undated; cuid35431 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - "Foundation of Linguistics", Undated; cuid35432 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - "Four Plays", 1967; cuid35433 (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - "Four Writings in One Writing", Undated; cuid35434 (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - "Fragment Bomb Wind," Parallax, 2000; cuid35435 (Box 38, Folder 47)
  - "Fragment: Death Cry", Undated; cuid35436 (Box 38, Folder 48)
  - "Fragments", Undated; cuid35437 (Box 38, Folder 49)
  - "From a Letter to D", Undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - "From a Play: Childpoem I", Undated; cuid35438 (Box 38, Folder 50)
  - "From: A Series of Statements as if They Were Absent from a Lecture", Undated; cuid35439 (Box 38, Folder 51)
  - "From Poem Hours", 1969; cuid35440 (Box 38, Folder 52)
  - "From Modernity to Postmodernity", Undated; cuid35441 (Box 38, Folder 53)
  - "From Rafael Alberti: 'Si Mi Voz Muriera en Tierra' ", Undated; cuid35442 (Box 38, Folder 54)
  - "Fucked Up, Thrown in Jail, in the Country of the Secret Police", Undated; cuid35443 (Box 38, Folder 55)
  - "The Function of the Avant-Garde: Possibilities", Undated; cuid35444 (Box 38, Folder 56)
  - "The Fundamental Rule in the Structure of Reality", Undated; cuid35445 (Box 38, Folder 57)
  - "The Future, Speaking Of or About", Undated; cuid35446 (Box 38, Folder 58)
  - "Gas Chamber", Undated; cuid35447 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - "The Genaeology of Machines", Undated; cuid35448 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "General Conjecture", Undated; cuid35449 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - "General Description of the World," Meta, Ltd., 1972; cuid35450 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "General Scheme", Undated; cuid35451 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - General Theory - First Draft, 1974; cuid35452 (Box 39, Folder 6, 7, Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "Geography Now and Then", 1988; cuid35453 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - "Germs and Peaches", Undated; cuid35454 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - "GGJ", Undated; cuid35455 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - "The Gift", Undated; cuid35456 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - "The Girl in Red and the Girl in Brown", Undated; cuid35457 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - "Gnosticism", Undated; cuid35458 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - "God", Undated; cuid35459 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - "Gome Performance", Undated; cuid35460 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - "Graham, Science, And Philosophy in the Soviet Union", Undated; cuid35461 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - "The Graph", Undated; cuid35462 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - "Graphemic Content of the English Language", Undated; cuid35463 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - "The Graphic Representation of the Sine Function, with 1/2x Reductions, Frame by Frame", Undated; cuid35464 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - "Grasp", 1983; cuid35465 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - "The Grasping of the Most Elementary", Undated; cuid35466 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - "Grounds for a Procedural Semiotics: Calculator Programming and an Outline of an Analysis of Marxism in Relation to 'The Structure of Reality' ", 1978; cuid35467 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - "Group Consensus in the Production of Literary Works", Undated; cuid35468 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - "Gulliver", 1975; cuid35469 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - "Ha-Ha", Undated; cuid35470 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - "Halwell's", Undated; cuid35471 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - "Hands", Undated; cuid35472 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Hazen/Pueblo Notebook, Undated; cuid35473 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - "Henderson Awake", Undated; cuid35474 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - "He Pearls That We", 2007; cuid35475 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - "Her Death", Undated; cuid35476 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - "Here and There", 1979; cuid35477 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - "Heroes, How They File Past", Undated; cuid35478 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - "Hiatus: Neutralization and Naïve Ratiocination", Undated; cuid35479 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - "Hideout Work Script Notes", Undated; cuid35480 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - "Hierarchical Structuring," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35481 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - "The Hierarchy of Entropies", Undated; cuid35482 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - "His Time", Undated; cuid35483 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - "History (A Meditation)", 1985; cuid35484 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - "History and Cancellation: The Pool at the Heart of the World", Undated; cuid35485 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - "History is a Condition of the Present, Not of the Past", Undated; cuid35486 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - "The History of Film", Undated; cuid35487 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - "Hollywood and Infinity", Undated; cuid35488 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - "Holly Would", Undated; cuid35489 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - "Holocaust: Representation as EMISSION Within Negative Cultural Space", Undated; cuid35490 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - "Hospital Comments", 1963; cuid35491 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - "The Hour of the Zeros", Undated; cuid35492 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - "How I Write", Undated; cuid35493 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - "How to Disappear", Undated; cuid35494 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - "Hymn, Home, and the End of the World: Script", 1984; cuid35495 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - "I", Undated; cuid35496 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - "I Am A Woman", Undated; cuid35497 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - "Icelandic Program", Undated; cuid35498 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - "Idaho", Undated; cuid35499 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - "The Idea of Switzerland in Lambdamoo", 1994; cuid35500 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - "Ideas on Time: Addenda to 'A Series of Works Leading…' ", Undated; cuid35501 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - "Ideal Realities," The Soho Weekly News, November 25 1976; cuid36110 (Box 77, Folder 24)
  - "The Ideological Machine", Undated; cuid35502 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - "The Ideological Enterprise", Undated; cuid35503 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - "I Die! I Faint! I Fail!", Undated; cuid35504 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - "I Don't Ask Sympathy For This", Undated; cuid35505 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - "I Have Watched…", Undated; cuid35506 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - "The Illuminated Countryside", 1969-1975; cuid35507 (Box 41, Folder 12, 13, 14)
  - "The Image/Representation", Undated; cuid35508 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - "Imagine", Undated; cuid35509 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - "I Model; You Take My Picture," CEPA Journal, 1988; cuid35510 (Box 41, Folder 17, 18)
  - "Implications", Undated; cuid35511 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - "Improvisations on the Human Element", Undated; cuid35512 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - "Incendiary Device Text", 1990; cuid35513 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - "Incorrect: Final Fire of the Video World", 2002; cuid35514 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - "The Increasing Blankness of Consumer Goods", Undated; cuid35515 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - "Increasingly My Life Turns Toward Violent Imbrication", Undated; cuid35516 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - "In Defense of (Linguistic) Obscurity", 1985; cuid35517 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - "Indexicality", Undated; cuid35518 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - "Individuals", 1973; cuid35519 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - "Inertia", Undated; cuid35520 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - "In Lieu of", 1977; cuid35521 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - "In Lieu of the Process (Napoleon)", Undated; cuid35522 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - "In Praise of Miro's 'Still Life With Old Shoe' ", Undated; cuid35523 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - "Inquisition: The Judgement of Art", Undated; cuid35524 (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - "Inscription", Undated; cuid35525 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - "Inscription Divisibility", Undated; cuid35526 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - "Inscription Types", Undated; cuid35527 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - "Instrumentality", Undated; cuid35528 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - "Interface", Undated; cuid35529 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - "Interim Report on Recent Work," Meta Ltd., 1973; cuid35530 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - "Internal Exile", 1985; cuid35531 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Internet Text, 1994-2006; cuid35532 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Internet Text, 1994-2006; cuid36149 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_29)
    "Internet Text" is an twelve year project in which Alan Sondheim posted textual works online. He describes it as a "long-standing online performance that interrogates the nature of computer-mediated consciousness and digital textuality."
  - "The Interpretation of Dreams", Undated; cuid35533 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - "Interrogation", Undated; cuid35534 (Box 41, Folder 42)
  - "Interruption Piece", Undated; cuid35535 (Box 41, Folder 43)
  - "Interview", Undated; cuid35536 (Box 41, Folder 44)
  - "In the 3rd World" by Alan Sondheim and Allison Ritch, 1982; cuid35537 (Box 41, Folder 45)
  - "(In These Woods, You Can't Go Home Again…)", 1977; cuid35538 (Box 41, Folder 46)
  - "Interview with Jerry Cullum," Art Papers, 1988; cuid35539 (Box 41, Folder 47)
  - "Introduction", Undated; cuid35540 (Box 41, Folder 48)
  - "Introduction", 1984; cuid35541 (Box 41, Folder 49)
  - "Introduction to the Writing", Undated; cuid35542 (Box 41, Folder 50)
  - "The Intransigent Divisions", Undated; cuid35543 (Box 41, Folder 51)
  - "Intransigent Projections", Undated; cuid35544 (Box 41, Folder 52)
  - "Invasion of the Feminine", Undated; cuid35545 (Box 41, Folder 53)
  - "Inventories", Undated; cuid35546 (Box 41, Folder 54)
  - "Invisible Children", Undated; cuid35547 (Box 41, Folder 55)
  - "I See My Films in the Following Manner", Undated; cuid35548 (Box 41, Folder 56)
  - "Is Perfection An Attribute or an Absence of Attributes", Undated; cuid35549 (Box 41, Folder 57)
  - "I Tell a Story", Undated; cuid35550 (Box 41, Folder 58)
  - "It's Been Said", Undated; cuid35551 (Box 41, Folder 59)
  - "I Want to Be a Woman", 1985; cuid35552 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - "I Want to Fuck You", Undated; cuid35553 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - "I Want to Report How I Found the World" Notebook, Undated; cuid35554 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - "I Went to the Movies", 1983; cuid35555 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - "Jabès", Undated; cuid35556 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - "The Jackson Pollock Essay," Art Papers, 1985; cuid35557 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - "Jennifer", 1998; cuid35558 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - "Jennifer in Phaedra," Backwoods Chaplet Series No. 43, 1999; cuid35559 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Jennifer, Julu, and Nikuko, 1997-2000; cuid36150 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_30)
    Jennifer, Julu, and Nikuko are personas or "avatars" through which Alan Sondheim expresses himself.